JACKSON ROBBINS

jackson@jacksonr.com (312) 429-7345

www.linkedin.com/in/jacksonrobbins606 https://jackrobbins1.github.io/

Chicago, IL 60622

WEB DEVELOPER AND TECH SUPPORT SPECIALIST

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack coding bootcamp graduate with more than 5 years of experience working directly with customers from industries that include technology, digital marketing, restaurant / hospitality, and beer. Proven track-record of providing excellent customer service and managing busy workload through strong organization and communication skills. Curious lifelong learner who enjoys studying complex systems and creative problem solving.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Customer Service
- Software Development
- Business Operations
- Written and Verbal Communication
- Troubleshooting and Problem Solving

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

LAMP (Linux Ubuntu, Apache, MySQL, PHP / CakePHP), MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git / Github, NPM, DigitalOcean, Apache Cordova, Ionic, Gulp, Salesforce, Excel, FreshDesk, Netsuite, RingCentral, Vermont Information Processing iDig, Datanyze, Spyfu, Yesware, Moz, Marketo, Microsoft Suite, and Google Suite

WORK EXPERIENCE

MicroTrain Technologies — Chicago, IL

April 2018 — Present

Student

MicroTrain Technologies provides instructor-led training to individuals and corporations. The company was founded in 1999 by Stan Van Nice and Dennis Muller and has provided innovative, hands-on training solutions to over 10,000 individual and corporate students.

- Intensive Full-Stack Web Development bootcamp lasting 10 weeks, with 40 hours of class per week.
- Acquired working proficiency with Ubuntu Linux and the software systems that compose two web stacks: LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP) and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, and Node.js).
- Learned hybrid mobile app development using Ionic.
- Learned about the challenges of internet security and the methods developers use to protect their systems and users.

TouchBistro — Chicago, IL

July 2017 — October 2017

Customer Care Specialist

TouchBistro is a Toronto-based tech company that develops a restaurant point of sale (POS) system for the iPad that is named best-in-class software by Business News Daily, G2 Crowd Reviews and other industry publications.

- Handle Tier 1 customer support requests from inbound calls, emails, and tickets.
- Assist clients with account options, ongoing subscriptions / billing, and troubleshooting technical issues to maximize retention.
- Tracked metrics and customer feature requests via Salesforce to inform product roadmap and sales strategy.
- Developed guidebooks to document procedures and best practices to improve the quality and consistency of the support team's customer service.

CH Distillery — Chicago, IL

February 2017 — June 2017

Off-Premise Brand Ambassador: Part-Time Consultant

- Managed tastings at key retail locations to engage customers and promote local brands.
- Reported metrics on tastings to tailor sales strategy for each retail account.

Sleeve a Message — Chicago, IL

February 2017 — July 2017

Sales Representative at Chicago-based start up selling custom bar coasters & coffee sleeves

- Worked with CEO and VP of Sales to craft sales prospecting strategy of new customers and align sales team on best practices for ongoing CRM to maximize sales.
- Led projects to test new product positioning based on insights from experience in on-premise beer sales.
- Managed sales for greater Chicagoland area and ensured timely execution of all orders.

DialogTech — Chicago, IL

May 2016 — January 2017

Account Development Representative of call attribution technology

DialogTech is a Chicago-based tech company that develops inbound call tracking software for digital marketers. The platform is used by more Fortune 500 companies than competing solutions and offers a comprehensive suite of tools to measure phone calls from online advertising, route calls from the context of customers' needs, and analyze customer to call center conversations with AI.

- Worked with business development team to execute a prospecting strategy built from marketing mix data and webinar attendee lists.
- Discuss with prospective clients the data our software collects and how it can improve and integrate with their existing marketing systems
- Managed webinar campaign targeting financial institutions and generated reporting on overall response rate and engagement metrics to inform future client prospecting.
- Among top performing reps on team & held ranking for most appointments won within 3 months at company.

Louis Glunz Beers Inc. — Lincolnwood, IL

October 2012 — February 2016

Sales Representative: Northside Territory — Promoted February 2014

Louis Glunz Beer is a family-owned importer and distributor of beers located in Lincolnwood, IL. The company has operated for 130 years and transformed the Chicago-area marketplace by introducing the premium import and craft beer categories to beer drinkers.

- Managed sales for 140+ accounts in the Lakeview neighborhood of Chicago (on & off-premise).
- Responsible for selling more than 50,000 cases of beer per year.
- Sold 6% more cases of beer in second year vs. prior year.
- Utilized iDig to track sales performance and identify opportunities or issues in my book of accounts.

Merchandiser — Promoted May 2013

Ambassador of Beer — October 2012

Costa Rica's Craft Brewing Company — Cartago, Costa Rica

June 2011— July 2011

Operations Assistant

- Created promotional media such as videos, brochures, and webpages.
- Trained as a brewmaster's assistant helping brewery operations and giving tours for customers.

EDUCATION

Macalester College — St. Paul, MN

August 2008 — May 2012

- Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (GPA: 3.10)
- Senior thesis: "Beer Festivals and Visitors' Motivations for Attending"

Associated Colleges of the Midwest: Costa Rica Field Research Program

January 2011 — May 2011

- Studied abroad and learned Spanish through living with host families and taking grammar courses.
- Conducted independent research of traditional palm wine production in Guanacaste for 2 months.